
02. Whats New in Google Analytics 4 GA4
Done
03. What are Google Analytics Anyway
Done

04. What Does Google Collect and How Does That Work

Google Collects:
Page ID
Language
Location
Time of day
Time spent on page
Actions on page
Device
Browser

Device orientation
Screen load time
Swipes and taps
Scrolling
Accelerometer(shakes)
Sensor activity
Game-specific data

<Depends on what the device does>
Temperature
What you say or hear
Health information
Frequency door opened
Inventory stored inside
Exercise routine


05. Why Is This Named Google Analytics 4 aka GA4
Done

06. Why Did Google Have to Change a Winning Formula
Skipped

07. What Are the Major Changes in GA4
Done

16. GA4 - Why Is There a New Analytics Interface
Done

17. GA4 Basic Vocabulary-Words and Terms to Know

[Attribution]: The act of assigning the credit for a sale or other type of conversion

[Attribution Model]: How credit is assigned for a conversion - a crucial bit of information for companies like Facebook and Google, who use this to claim that their ads were responsible for the sale

[Conversion]: Another key success metric - refers to users doing the activity that your organization values, such as buying something, visiting an auto showroom, subscribing to a newsletter, etc.

[Dimension]: A trackable characteristic of your users. What it refers to are things like the type of smartphone, or browser, or screen size of the device of your user.
GA4 has two categories of dimensions: 1) default 2) custom
Default: User acquisition, Session acquisition, User Engagement, Monetization, Demographics, Technology

[Engagement]

[Event]: When a user does something on your site/app, such as playing a video, downloading a pdf, clicking on a link, logging in to a site, etc.

Google broadly categorizes these events as 1) Automatically collected, 2) Recommended 3) Custom


[Goal]: Something you tell GA4 to specifically track as the endpoint of user behavior

Conversions are a typical goal, but sometimes the goal is just to see how many pages a user looks at. Or how long they spend scrolling through your app.

[Hit]:An interaction with your site or app that sends data to GA4.
EXAMPLE: loading a page on a site, adding an item to a shopping cart, 
sharing or liking content via social media.
NOTE: what was a “hit” in UA, is now an “event” in GA4

[Metric]:A specific sum, average or ratio of a specific kind of data collected. 
EXAMPLE: Active users, ad exposure, first opens, new users, user 
retention, lifetime value, or PMAU/DAU

[Pageviews]:How many pages on your site were looked at by your users. 
Not the same as users. Hopefully each user will load and look at multiple 
pages.
NOTE: Once the backbone of analytics analysis, this has been somewhat 
displaced by “events.”

[Segment]:A specific grouping of users or user behavior. Basically, this is a filter 
that you apply to all your data to focus in on details.
GA4 has 3 main types, 1) User, 2) Session, 3) Event. 
EXAMPLE: A segment containing all the users from Texas who opened 
your app last Tuesday after the ads ran there, and clicked on the special 
offer coupon.

[Session]: When a user opens your app in the foreground, or has your page open in 
a browser and no other session is active. Duration default is 30 minutes, 
but you can change that. 
NOTE: GA4 changes how sessions are tracked. If the campaign source 
changes, that’s still the same session. If a session starts at 11:55 p.m. on 
one day and ends at 12:10 the next, that’s still one session.

[Source/Medium]: Source is where the user came from, and Medium is the general 
category of that source. Again, this sounds abstract.
EXAMPLE: You’ll see your site traffic origin reported as Social / 
Facebook. That means your users came in via a social media network, in 
this case Facebook. Or maybe it’s Social / Twitter. Or Organic Search / 
Google.

[User Acquisition]: How users are being directed to your site or app. Very important to site 
owners, who want to know what working – ads, social media posts, viral 
videos, SEO, etc.

22. GA4 - Monetization and User Retention
Done

23. GA4 User Reports - Demographics and Tech
Done

24. GA4 Explore - Where You Can Build Your Own Reports
進入path exploration
可以把左邊的方塊拖曳至右邊的segment 
以篩選出不同條件的users都去了哪些地方

25. GA4 User Interface - Advertising and Configure
Configure 被藏起來了

26. Basic Configurations When Starting out in GA4
Engagement => Events

Admin => Enable Google signals data collection

27. Configuring Ecommerce Conversion Events and Building a Funnel
Creat event
Funnel step



Source: PL google analytics 4 fundamentals